John E. Hogan papers, Inclusive: 1916-1998, undated; Bulk: 1974-1998.
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
- Environment, 1974-1997, undated; 2
  - Endangered Species, Endangered Species Recovery Act of 1997, Correspondence, 1997 July (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Endangered Species, Extinction, Clippings and Reports, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Endangered Species, Fish and Wildlife Service, Publication, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Endangered Species, National Endangered Species Act Reform Coalition, Newsletters and Summaries, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Endangered Species, “The Endangered Species Act: Making Innocent Species the Enemy”, Publication, 1995 April (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Environmental Law, American Law Institute-American Bar Association, Course of Study, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, Binder, “Clean Water Reference Book” (1 of 3), 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, Binder, “Clean Water Reference Book” (2 of 3), 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, Binder, “Clean Water Reference Book” (3 of 3), 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, Pesticide Cancellation Proceedings, Correspondence, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Quality Incentives Program, Proposed Rules, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Working Group, Conservation Compliance, Briefings and Statements, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), Public Law 104, 1996 August 3 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990, Title XVI Research, 1996 April 11 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Food Safety, Food Quality Protection Act of 1996, Binder, Implementation Update, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Food Safety, Food Quality Protection Act of 1996, Correspondence and Reports, 1993-1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Food Safety, Food Quality Protection Act of 1996, Implementation, Correspondence and Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Food Safety, Food Quality Protection Act of 1996, Report, Status of Implementation, 1997 October 1 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Food Safety, Food Quality Protection Act of 1996, Reports and Supplemental Documents (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Food Safety, Food Quality Protection Act of 1996, Summary and Analysis, 1996 August 3 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Food Safety, Publications, 1978-1994 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Food Safety, Report, “Minor Uses and Implementation of the Food Quality Protection Act of 1996”, 1997 July 10 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Food Safety, Report, “The Pressing Need for Food Safety Education”, 1996 September (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Food Safety, Separation Sheets, Publications (1 of 2), 1974-1995 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Food Safety, Separation Sheets, Publications (2 of 2), 1974-1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Food Safety, Sub-Council Council Working Group on Food Safety, Issue Papers, 1982 September 13 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Food Safety, The National Research Council, Report, “Toward Healthful Diets”, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Forest Service, Report, “New Perspectives for Managing the National Forest System”, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Forests, Old-Growth, Summary, “Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement”, 1994 February (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Forests, Patrick Moore, Article, “Pacific Spirit: The Forest Reborn”, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Forests, Recreation Fees (H.R. 2107), Correspondence and Legislative Bills, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Forests, Report, “Forested Landscapes in Perspective”, 1997, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Forests, Separation Sheets, Publications, 1987-1994 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Forestry Incentive Programs and Stewardship Incentive Programs, Correspondence and Reports, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S. Forest Service: Fees for Recreation Special-Use Permits Do Not Reflect Fair Market Value”, 1996 December (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Insecticides, Guatemala MOSCAMED Program, Analysis, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Legislative Drafting, Practices and Procedures, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act Amendments of 1981, 1996 April 11 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - National Grain and Feed Foundation, Report, “Large-Scale Land Idling Has Retarded Growth of U.S. Agriculture”, 1994 May (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Organic Program, Proposed Rules, “Federal Register”, Clippings, 1997 December 16 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Natural Resources Conservation Service, Proposed Changes to Handbook, Notice, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Nitrite, Comptroller General, Report, “Does Nitrite Cause Cancer?”, 1980 January 31 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Nitrite, Interagency Working Group on Nitrite Research, Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Office of Technology Assessment, “Agriculture, Trade, and Environment: Achieving Complementary Policies”, Briefs, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Pesticides, Book, “Regulating Pesticides in Food: The Delaney Paradox”, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Pesticides, Chem Life, Report, “Consumer Pesticides: Why We Need Them, and What They Do”, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Pesticides, Chemical Carcinogens, “Federal Register”, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Pesticides, Committee Rules and Rules for Investigative Hearings”, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Pesticides, Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), Congressional Research Service, Correspondence and Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Pesticides, Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), Preemption of Local Authority, Clippings and Printed Materials, 1987-1992 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Pesticides, Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), Preemption of Local Authority, Testimonies, 1992 March (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Pesticides, Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), Proposed Amendments, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Pesticides, Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), Registration Fees, Correspondence and Reports, 1988-1997 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pesticides, Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), Research, 1977-1997 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Pesticides, Federal Pesticide Reform Act of 1985, Briefing Book, 1985 March (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Pesticides, Food Quality Protection Act of 1995, Section-by-Section Summaries, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Pesticides, “From Lab to Label”, Presentation Slides, 1994-1997 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Pesticides, Government Performance and Results Act, Guide and Proposal, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Pesticides, Separation Sheets, Publications, 1986-1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Pollution, Separation Sheets, Publications, 1987-1993 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Prescription Drugs, Prescription Drug User Fee Act of 1992, “Federal Register”, 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Property Rights, Property Rights Bill (H.R. 925), Statements, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Reducing Cancer Risks Through Diet, Correspondence and Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - The Wilderness Society, Ancient Forest Economics, Binder, 1991-1992, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Water Rights, H.R. 925, Memorandum, 1995 April 11 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Wetlands, 1996 Farm Bill, Report, “Highly Erodible Land and Wetland Conservation” (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Wetlands, Cancelled 1989 Delineation Manual, “Federal Manual for Identifying and Delineating Jurisdictional Wetlands”, 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Wetlands, Clean Water Act, Section 404, Statements, 1990-1997 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Wetlands, Clipping, “Government to Tighten Wetlands Regulations”, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Wetlands, Congressional Research Service, Articles, 1994-1997 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Wetlands, Corps of Engineers Wetlands Delineation Manual, 1987 January (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Wetlands, Early Contract Termination Provisions, Notice, 1996 April (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Wetlands, Memorandum of Agreement, Clean Water Act, 1994 November (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Wetlands, Natural Resource Conservation Service, Memorandum, 1996 December 13 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Wetlands, Separation Sheets, Publications, 1987-1997 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Wetlands, Tulloch Case, Legal Opinion, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Wetlands, Wetlands Reserve Program, Fact Sheets, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Federal Law, 1979-1997, undated; 3
  Series III. Federal Law, a small series, contains materials that cover a broad spectrum of federal topics. Most of the materials are comprised of updates, proposals, revisions, and opinions. The materials in this series are in excellent condition.
  - 1994 Federal Law Update II (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - 1996 Farm Bill, Peanut Program, Court Cases, 1996 May (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Banking and Litigation, Proposals and Responses, 1994-1997 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Church and State, History, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Guidelines, Child Abuse, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Civil Rights and the U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Copyright, Proposals, Extensions, Fair Use, and Criminal Infringement, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Delegation to Private Parties in American Constitutional Law, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Encryption, Legal Issues, Selected References, and Control, 1997 September (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - "Ending the Era of Big Government, Balancing America’s Budget" (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "Ending the Era of Big Government, Balancing America’s Budget" (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Exhaustion and Administrative Function, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Federal Law Updates, 1994-1997 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Federal Regulation of Anti-Abortion and Other Political Protest, 1994 October (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Federal Sanctions Imposed for Violations of the Controlled Substance Act, 1994 September (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Flat Tax Proposals: An Overview, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Freedom of Speech and Press, Exceptions to the First Amendment, 1994 July (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Government Performance and Results Act (P.L. 103-62), 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Human Cloning and Genetic Information Privacy, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Impeachment: An Overview of Constitutional Provisions, Procedure, and Practice, 1995 February (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Independent Council Provisions, Ethics, 1994-1997 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Information Privacy, 1997 September (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Interstate Compacts, History, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Introduction to the Law, Practice, and Procedure of Congressional Inquiry, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - John E. Hogan v. Office of Personnel Management, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Moorhead-Schroeder Patent Reform Act, An Overview of H.R. 3460, 1996 June (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Oversight of Congress, 1988-1995 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Point of Order Against an Unauthorized Expenditure in an Appropriation Bill, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Point of Order Against Legislative Language in an Appropriation Bill, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Professional Responsibility for Legislative Attorney, Course Materials, 1994-1997 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Proposal to Change Corn and Soybean Futures Contracts for Chicago, 1997 September (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Prosecutorial Discretion, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Public Contracts (P.L. 103-355), 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Public Performance Right in Digital Audio Transmission of Sound Recordings, 1996 February (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Research on “Use Immunity”, 1988-1993 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Speech and Debate Clause Common Law Tort Exemption, 1988-1991 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - State Legislative Proposals Concerning Cloning of Human Beings, 1997 March (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Subpoenas and Appropriated Funds, 1995-1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Supreme Court Opinions and Federal Judge Terms, 1995-1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Television Satellite Carrier License, 1996 July (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Administration’s Case for “Hospital Cost Containment”, 1979 June (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - The Death Penalty, Supreme Court and Congress, Research, 1993-1994 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act, 1994 September (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Unfunded Mandates Reform Act, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Richard Nixon Impeachment Materials, 1973-1974; 4
  By far the smallest series in the collection, Series V. contains a publication list and statements pertaining to the impeachment hearings for President Richard Nixon. Overall, the materials in this series are in excellent condition.
  - House Committee on the Judiciary, Hearings, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - House Committee on the Judiciary, Impeachment Inquiry, Publication List, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - House Committee on the Judiciary, Statement of Information, 1974 May-June (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Statement of Information, Hearings, Book IV, Part 2, 1974 May-June (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Statement of Information, Hearings, Book V, Part 1, 1974 May-June (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Statements, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Trade, 1977-1997, undated; 5
  Trade consists of materials pertaining to agriculture and trade. There is a large section of reports produced by the General Accounting Office, particularly relating to trade between the United States and Mexico. The series covers a wide range of topics including food aid, nutrition labeling, and various trade deals such as the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) and the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT). Overall, the series is in excellent condition.
  - Agricultural Trade File, Congressional Research Service, Reports, 1994-1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Agriculture, Trade Jurisdiction, Analysis and Correspondence, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Commodity Credit Corporation, Budget History, Binder, 1979-1989 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Commodity Credit Corporation, Budget History, Reports, 1977-1990 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Commodity Exchange Act, Binder, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Budget Office, Report, “A CBO Study: A Budgetary and Economic Analysis of the North American Free Trade Agreement”, 1993 July (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Research Service, Asian-Pacific Economic Cooperation, Correspondence and Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - “Dictionary of International Agricultural Trade”, Reports, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Exports, Congressional Research Service, Reports, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Exports, Foreign Agriculture Service, Briefings, 1995, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Fast Track Amendment, Proposal for Fast Track Authority, 1994 June 16 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Food Aid, “Brief Description of Food Aid Authorities”, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Food Aid, Congressional Research Service, Report, “P.L. 480 Food Aid: History and Legislation, Programs, and Policy Issues”, 1994 April 6 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Food Labeling, “A User’s Manual”, 1992-1994 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Food Labeling, American Consumers, Fact Sheets and Reports, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Food Labeling, Clippings and Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Food Labeling, H.R. 4739, Correspondence and Printed Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Food Labeling, Separation Sheets, Publications, 1988-1997 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Food Labeling, Small Business Exemptions, Meeting Notes, 1993 April 27 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Food Safety and Inspection Service, Nutrition Labeling, Information Kit, 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Food Safety and Inspection Service, Nutrition Labeling of Meat and Poultry Products, Final Rule, 1993 January 6 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Food Safety and Inspection Service, Nutrition Labeling of Meat and Poultry Products, Proposed Rule, 1991 November 27 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Agricultural Service, “Ag Exporter”, “Mexico: A Blooming Market for U.S. Agricultural Products”, 1992 June (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - General Accounting Office, 1995 Farm Bill, Exports, Reports and Separation Sheets, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - General Accounting Office, General Government Division, Report, Final Act of the Uruguay Round, 1994 July 22 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “Agricultural Trade”, 1994 December (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “Automated Export System”, 1997 November (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “Cargo Preference Requirements”, 1994 September (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “Mexican Oil”, 1992 March (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “North American Free Trade Agreement: Assessment of Major Issues, Volume 1”, 1993 September (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “North American Free Trade Agreement: Assessment of Major Issues, Volume 2”, 1993 September (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “Payments, Clearance, and Settlement”, 1997 June (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “Some U.S. Wood Furniture Firms Relocated From Los Angeles Area to Mexico”, 1991 April (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Energy”, 1991 May (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Trade: Concerns About the Adequacy of Border Infrastructure”, 1991 May (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Trade: Extent to Which Mexican Horticultural Exports Complement U.S. Production”, 1991 March (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Trade: Impact of Liberalization in the Agricultural Sector”, 1991 March (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Trade: Information on Environmental Regulations and Enforcement”, 1991 May (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Trade: Information on Wages, Fringe Benefits, and Workers’ Rights”, 1991 May (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Trade: Survey of U.S. Border Infrastructure Needs”, 1991 November (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - General Accounting Office, Report, “U.S.-Mexico Trade: Trends and Impediments in Agricultural Trade”, 1990 January (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - General Accounting Office, Report on High Value Product Exports to Taiwan, Malaysia, and Indonesia, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - General Accounting Office, Separation Sheets, Publications (1 of 2), 1989-1997 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - General Accounting Office, Separation Sheets, Publications (2 of 2), 1989-1997 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, Congressional Budget Office, Estimates, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, Economic Benefits, Reports, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, Funding, Correspondence and Press Releases, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - General Agriculture, Separation Sheets, Publications (1 of 2), 1977-1998 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - General Agriculture, Separation Sheets, Publications (2 of 2), 1977-1998 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Imports, Report, “Cotton Textile Imports: Consequences of the Status Quo and Urgently Needed Actions”, circa 1984 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Multilateral Trade, “Agreement on Technical Barriers to Trade”, circa 1994 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Assessment by Department of Agriculture, 1994 October 10 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Briefing Synopsis, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Congressional Research Service, Information Packet, 1993-1997 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Effects on Agriculture, Fact Sheets and Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Implementation, Cost Estimates, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Legislative Bill (H.R. 3450), 1993 November (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, “NAFTA: An Early Assessment”, Report, NAFTA Economic Monitoring Taskforce, 1994 December (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Report, “The NAFTA Supplemental Agreements”, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Section 321(e), Data, Correspondence and Report, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Separation Sheets, Publications, 1990-1993 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, Summary of Joint Recommendations, House and Senate Committees, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - North American Free Trade Agreement, “Texts of Agreement, Implementing Bill, Statement of Administrative Action, and Required Supporting Statements”, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Office of the Clerk, Minutes, “Public Hearing on Agriculture Trade into the 21st Century”, 1997 March 18 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Sanitation, “Agreement on the Application of Sanitary and Phytosanitary Measures”, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Trade Representative, Perot/Choate NAFTA Book, “Correcting the Record”, 1993 September (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Uruguay Round, Implementation, Agreements and Statements, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Uruguay Round, Source Book, “The Uruguay Round of Multilateral Trade Negotiations”, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Uruguay Round, World Trade Organization, Correspondence and Talking Points, 1994 November (Box 24, Folder 7)